<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mudler blog</title>
    <link>https://mudler.pm/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mudler blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 06:02:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mudler.pm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Whut?! Sabayon Community Repositories is here!</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2016/04/whut-sabayon-community-repositories-is.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 06:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2016/04/whut-sabayon-community-repositories-is.html</guid>
      <description>Maaaaaaaaaaaaany dependencies for enman… Still, he&amp;hellip; Tedel - Apr 1, 2016
Maaaaaaaaaaaaany dependencies for enman…
Still, here we go! :D</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whut?! Sabayon Community Repositories is here!</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2016/04/whut-sabayon-community-repositories-is.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 06:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2016/04/whut-sabayon-community-repositories-is.html</guid>
      <description>Hello users,
Time passed when i first wrote the article &amp;ldquo;[Part 1] Building Gentoo and Sabayon packages in your machine locally or remotely with Docker and Cloud Services&amp;rdquo; that was going to be divided into parts. But things changed amazingly fast and there is better news, I wrote up a suite of tools that makes the whole operation much easier, thanks also to +Ben Roberts (optiz0r) who contributed in the development and he is also kindly sponsoring the buildserver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Updates: Rpi2 joins to testing boards, Mate testing repository, Sabayon devkit</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2016/02/updates-rpi2-joins-to-testing-boards.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 10:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2016/02/updates-rpi2-joins-to-testing-boards.html</guid>
      <description>Updates, TMiD (This Month in the Dev world)
Something landed here! Thanks to +Ben Roberts for the donation!
ARM Marsala, the board that +Ben Roberts was so kind to donate has just landed here, and i&amp;rsquo;m very happy about it, because that means that i can test against the board again myself.
I&amp;rsquo;m glad also to announce that the ROS framework and some other goodies(among of them firefox and libreoffice) have been pushed into our ARM repo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon on RaspberryPi2 </title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2016/01/tech-preview-sabayon-on-raspberrypi2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 05:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2016/01/tech-preview-sabayon-on-raspberrypi2.html</guid>
      <description>hi, this is a really good new are there chances o&amp;hellip; Unknown - Feb 6, 2016
hi, this is a really good new
are there chances of having sabayon on Raspberry PI (not PI2)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon on RaspberryPi2 </title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2016/01/tech-preview-sabayon-on-raspberrypi2.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 05:02:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2016/01/tech-preview-sabayon-on-raspberrypi2.html</guid>
      <description>As anticipated on Sabayon Linux site releases notes, that day was going to be close.
ARM meet Sabayon, Sabayon meet ARM.
The approach to the ARM(hfp) support will be different from the previous attempt, we are not going to support kernels for each different board we intend to build images, instead we will release cutted images with vendor-kernel to avoid incompatibilities and unexpected features. This is what almost every distribution does for tons of reasons, among them i want just to underline that in those years we have seen a lot of new ARM boards out of there and we can&amp;rsquo;t just support all of them, mantain a kernel branch for each one would results low QA (since our dev-team is small) and probably in hard decision to be made when support will be dropped from vendors (think also on how short is a board lifespan, and how projects dies quickly).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1] Building Gentoo and Sabayon packages in your machine locally or remotely with Docker and Cloud Services</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 07:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</guid>
      <description>With spawning a compilation, the second line (with&amp;hellip; fusion809 - Nov 4, 2015
With spawning a compilation, the second line (with the package you wish to merge) is it possible to point to a specific version of a package. For example, atm I&amp;rsquo;d like to merge app-editors/atom-1.2.0 from the Sabayon overlay, do I have to enter it as `app-editors/atom-1.2.0 &amp;ndash;overlay sabayon` or `=app-editors/atom-1.2.0 &amp;ndash;overlay sabayon`?
In section 3 I think you gave incorrect syntax, although it may be because of formatting limitations imposed by blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1] Building Gentoo and Sabayon packages in your machine locally or remotely with Docker and Cloud Services</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 07:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</guid>
      <description>As previously anticipated in the previous blog post, here i explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on with Sabayon Docker images, and how can the Official Sabayon images help you in developing/deploying your application. In this article, i&amp;rsquo;ll show how to build Sabayon/Gentoo packages using Docker.
I&amp;rsquo;ll cover five cases and will be divided in differents articles:
You want to build packages locally You want to remotely build packages You want to host an overlay or a Sabayon repository and want your packages to get built on each push to the git repository You want to track remote repository changes and test (useful if you can&amp;rsquo;t setup a webhook) Setup an Entropy repo with a Docker image, and how to mantain packages In future, i&amp;rsquo;ll write also a post also on how to track the packages remotely with CircleCi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon: testers, testers, testers</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/10/sabayon-testers-testers-testers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/10/sabayon-testers-testers-testers.html</guid>
      <description>I will give it a go installing new motherboard tod&amp;hellip; Unknown - Oct 4, 2015
I will give it a go installing new motherboard today will start testing after thate
Thanks for your efforts , please remember to file a bug for whatever problem you will face!
I have jut installed a new motherboard,it is a msi z97a the only problem so far is I cant install sabayon in uefi mode I am runing 15.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon: testers, testers, testers</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/10/sabayon-testers-testers-testers.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 14:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/10/sabayon-testers-testers-testers.html</guid>
      <description>Sabayon, official call for testers (and well, developers are welcome too)
Testers, come to us Probably most of you already have seen Ballmer in show-mode
Also if controversial, it was a quite funny commercial / raindance move, balls included. But i can say that he is wrong, testers are as important as developers.
Consider helping Sabayon in a different way: testing it.
I am here, begging YOU for some help. The more the merrier!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon 15.10 press release</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-1510-press-release.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 11:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-1510-press-release.html</guid>
      <description>Image: an ancient hen-foot print found on Mars (Mars Photo credit to NASA)
Sabayon 15.10 is a modern and easy to use Linux distribution based on Gentoo, following an extreme, yet reliable, rolling release model.
This is a monthly release generated, tested and published to mirrors by our build servers containing the latest and greatest collection of software available in the Entropy repositories.
The ChangeLog files related to this release are available on our mirrors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon is moving to KDE Plasma 5.4</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 10:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</guid>
      <description>Sabayon is officially moving to Plasma 5, please read if you are a KDE Sabayon user.
KDM is going to be removed! migrate to SDDM now!
Yes, finally we are moving on.
While KDE 4 was a pretty stable DM, Plasma 5 brings awesomeness and, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, it&amp;rsquo;s the future.
From KDM to SDDM We tried to do our best to make the transition as smooth as possible and automatic, but if your system just got broken here is why: the KDE team announced SDDM as the default KDE display manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 05:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks, Unfortunately running in VirtualBox 4.3.28&amp;hellip; Unknown - Sep 3, 2015
Thanks, Unfortunately running in VirtualBox 4.3.28, NetworkManager is crashing and can&amp;rsquo;t access desktop. :(
Thanks for your feedback, i run the image on VirtualBox 4.3.28 as well without problems, can you try to change the Network Adaptor type under the image settings, Network-&amp;gt; Advanced -&amp;gt; Card type
Thanks, your tip solve the startup. Dolphin link from main menu is broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 05:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</guid>
      <description>!! WARNING - HERE BE DRAGONS !!
Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD Tech preview is available for download
This release is just for testing only, it is just a preview of Plasma5 on Sabayon for those of you that wants just to snoop on what&amp;rsquo;s going on without touching your system.
If you want to install Plasma 5 with the community repository, follow those instructions.
Known issues: Dolphin Shortcut on favorites is not working Desktop isn&amp;rsquo;t in folderview so you can&amp;rsquo;t quickly access to the install icon, but the installer is present (search for &amp;ldquo;Calamares&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Installer&amp;rdquo; in the Plasma menu) No Sabayon artwork is present, plasma is vanilla Please, if you encounter other issues let us know, Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Plasma 5.4, available on Plasma5 Sabayon community repository</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that Plasma 5.4 is available on Sabayon Plasma5 community repository.
Plasma 5.4
The KDE team announced on 25 August the release of Plasma 5.4:
This release of Plasma brings many nice touches for our users such as much improved high DPI support, KRunner auto-completion and many new beautiful Breeze icons. It also lays the ground for the future with a tech preview of Wayland session available. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping a few new components such as an Audio Volume Plasma Widget, monitor calibration tool and the User Manager tool comes out beta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>on Calamares, Docker and Sabayon</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/on-calamares-docker-and-sabayon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 04:29:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/on-calamares-docker-and-sabayon.html</guid>
      <description>Since i became Sabayon developer, i started to work on customizing it and giving some love to the entropy packages.
A lot as been done in those months, and you can see that picking up a &amp;ldquo;-dev&amp;rdquo; image from our mirrors.
After giving to the entropy packages a fullfill of love (systemd was bumped, ati-drivers and nvidia-drivers as well to be in line with upstream, implemented iptables saving rules for systemd, &amp;hellip; ) then we decided that the time of Anaconda installer was finished.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google at Home installation [#1 Howto]</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/10/google-at-home-installation-1-howto.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 03:04:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/10/google-at-home-installation-1-howto.html</guid>
      <description>The first post of a series that will guide you to install and configure your domotic environment with Google@Home (following updates)
Introduction I&amp;rsquo;m starting in the blog a new series of posts illustrating the features of G@H as they are being developed, and how you can start to play with it.
This time we are going to see how to install it correctly, how to handle the basic configuration needed to start and we will install the Wikipedia plugin to allow to query wikipedia with our voice (you can lookup stuff on wikipedia just saying &amp;ldquo;wikipedia house&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitInsight, predicting your github contribs calendar</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/08/gitinsight-predicting-your-github.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2014 02:59:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/08/gitinsight-predicting-your-github.html</guid>
      <description>Predicting github contrib calendar with Perl and PDL
Premise : this is my first time using PDL
Lately i had the chance to put my hands on PDL, i was glad to discover that it&amp;rsquo;s awesome!
I come from a matlab/octave and Mathematica background, at first was a bit difficult to dig thru the PDL equivalents functions and i have to admit that PyMC has some fancy stuff that require a lot of code to implement in PDL and i wanted to borrow in that case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Deeme</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/06/introducing-deeme.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 02:57:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/06/introducing-deeme.html</guid>
      <description>Introducing Deeme a database-agnostic driven event emitter base-class.
Deeme is a database-agnostic driven event emitter base-class. Deeme allows you to define binding subs on different points in multiple applications, and execute them later, in another worker with a switchable backend database. It is handy if you have to attach subs to events that are delayed in time and must be fixed. It is strongly inspired by (and a rework of) Mojo::EventEmitter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G@H updates! (5)</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/gh-updates-5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 02:55:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/gh-updates-5.html</guid>
      <description>This post is an update of the current status of the Google@Home project. Google@Home tries to bring domotic control in your home using Google Services for Speech Synthesis and Text-to-Speech. Finally a sketchup of the Android App!
That&amp;rsquo;s the current status of the project:
The GSoC student :
RPC server integration, fully pluggable with Mojolicious (better than the one was in the proposal, less dependencies since that framework will be used also for the UI) RPC Parser service, that forward request to the Parser that handles the actions to be made (by voice) Finished SQLite Schema with DBIx::Class, working on the SQLite Backend, Parser and deployer (using DBIx::Class::DeploymentHandler) facing some bugs encountered in his way This is what i have done so far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G@H updates! (4)</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/06/gh-updates-4.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 02:52:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/06/gh-updates-4.html</guid>
      <description>This post is an update of the current status of the Google@Home project. Google@Home tries to bring domotic control in your home using Google Services for Speech Synthesis and Text-to-Speech. It is also planned a web interface to control the embedded nodes in the current environment. In this post i&amp;rsquo;ll report also the work by the GSoC student so far
During this period i haven&amp;rsquo;t much time to code, due to my knee surgery, but that&amp;rsquo;s the current status of the project:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>love for pushbullet</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/love-for-pushbullet.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 02:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/love-for-pushbullet.html</guid>
      <description>Well, if you don&amp;rsquo;t know what pushbullet is, it&amp;rsquo;s a free-less-complicated version of what pusher.com does, unifying push&amp;rsquo;s across all the devices. In this article i&amp;rsquo;ll show how to implement pushbullet api in perl, in few lines of code.
Pushbullet enables to notify instantly to all your devices a message, a link, a file, an address or even a list of todo&amp;rsquo;s (and probably more) : that can be quite handy if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to setup an entire notification system, want to avoid the hassle of email alerts (that&amp;rsquo;s not a critique, but i hate having my mailbox full of short report status messages ) or if you want that all your clients are notified immediately.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple issues in libXfont</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/multiple-issues-in-libxfont.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 02:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/multiple-issues-in-libxfont.html</guid>
      <description>_
These months are full of bugs to put hands on, there are multiple vulnerabilities (3) found in libXfont that trusts the font server protocol data, and not verifying that the values will not overflow or cause other damage._
From the Alan Coopersmith announce:
Ilja van Sprundel, a security researcher with IOActive, has discovered several issues in the way the libXfont library handles the responses it receives from xfs servers, and has worked with X.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CVE-2014-0196: Linux kernel pty layer race</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/cve-2014-0196-linux-kernel-pty-layer.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 02:38:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/05/cve-2014-0196-linux-kernel-pty-layer.html</guid>
      <description>Two days ago a temible exploit was released for local privilage escalation in the linux kernel. The bug was found on the 29th of April: memory corruption via a race in pty write handling , affected kernels are 2.6.31 -&amp;gt; 3.14rcX
The n_tty_write function in drivers/tty/n_tty.c in the Linux kernel through 3.14.3 does not properly manage tty driver access in the &amp;ldquo;LECHO &amp;amp; !OPOST&amp;rdquo; case, which allows local users to cause a denial of service (memory corruption and system crash) or gain privileges by triggering a race condition involving read and write operations with long strings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G@H updates! (3)</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/03/gh-updates-3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2014 02:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/03/gh-updates-3.html</guid>
      <description>This post is an update of the current status of the Google@Home project. Google@Home tries to bring domotic control in your home using Google Services for Speech Synthesis and Text-to-Speech. It is also planned a web interface to control the embedded nodes in the current environment.
During this period i focused on fixing bugs, microphone settings and some structural restyling
This is a small summary of the changes ( for a complete list, check commit diffs in github page) :</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>G@H updates! (2)</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/04/this-post-is-update-of-current-status.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 02:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/04/this-post-is-update-of-current-status.html</guid>
      <description>This post is an update of the current status of the Google@Home project. Google@Home tries to bring domotic control in your home using Google Services for Speech Synthesis and Text-to-Speech. It is also planned a web interface to control the embedded nodes in the current environment.
During this week i focused on fixing bug and few structural enhancements
This is a small summary of the changes:
[fix] Plugin can be removed safetly master now can load node configurations by their backends (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google at Home updates</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2014/03/google-at-home-updates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2014 02:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2014/03/google-at-home-updates.html</guid>
      <description>_
This post is an update of the current status of the Google@Home project. Google@Home tries to bring domotic control in your home using Google Services for Speech Synthesis and Text-to-Speech. It is also planned a web interface to control the embedded nodes in the current environment.
_
For now it&amp;rsquo;s still required to manually set-up the YAML file to configure which nodes belongs to the network, but if you set up some RaspberryPi on the network and a master node that has installed MongoDB the dispatchment of the commands and of the voice (so you can command everything by issuing commands on one node) works for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome!</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/welcome.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 01:40:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/welcome.html</guid>
      <description>This is my blog, it&amp;rsquo;s powered it was powered with Perl and Mojolicious. Enjoy! You will find here some interesting perl posts and updates for the projects where i am involved.
Unfortunately i had to move to blogger, due to time issues. Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
