<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kde on Mudler blog</title>
    <link>https://mudler.pm/tags/kde/</link>
    <description>Recent content in kde on Mudler blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 11:07:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mudler.pm/tags/kde/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon 15.10 press release</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-1510-press-release.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 11:07:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-1510-press-release.html</guid>
      <description>Image: an ancient hen-foot print found on Mars (Mars Photo credit to NASA)
Sabayon 15.10 is a modern and easy to use Linux distribution based on Gentoo, following an extreme, yet reliable, rolling release model.
This is a monthly release generated, tested and published to mirrors by our build servers containing the latest and greatest collection of software available in the Entropy repositories.
The ChangeLog files related to this release are available on our mirrors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon is moving to KDE Plasma 5.4</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 10:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</guid>
      <description>Sabayon is officially moving to Plasma 5, please read if you are a KDE Sabayon user.
KDM is going to be removed! migrate to SDDM now!
Yes, finally we are moving on.
While KDE 4 was a pretty stable DM, Plasma 5 brings awesomeness and, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, it&amp;rsquo;s the future.
From KDM to SDDM We tried to do our best to make the transition as smooth as possible and automatic, but if your system just got broken here is why: the KDE team announced SDDM as the default KDE display manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 05:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</guid>
      <description>Thanks, Unfortunately running in VirtualBox 4.3.28&amp;hellip; Unknown - Sep 3, 2015
Thanks, Unfortunately running in VirtualBox 4.3.28, NetworkManager is crashing and can&amp;rsquo;t access desktop. :(
Thanks for your feedback, i run the image on VirtualBox 4.3.28 as well without problems, can you try to change the Network Adaptor type under the image settings, Network-&amp;gt; Advanced -&amp;gt; Card type
Thanks, your tip solve the startup. Dolphin link from main menu is broken.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Preview: Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 05:46:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/tech-preview-sabayon-plasma-5-livecd.html</guid>
      <description>!! WARNING - HERE BE DRAGONS !!
Sabayon Plasma 5 LiveCD Tech preview is available for download
This release is just for testing only, it is just a preview of Plasma5 on Sabayon for those of you that wants just to snoop on what&amp;rsquo;s going on without touching your system.
If you want to install Plasma 5 with the community repository, follow those instructions.
Known issues: Dolphin Shortcut on favorites is not working Desktop isn&amp;rsquo;t in folderview so you can&amp;rsquo;t quickly access to the install icon, but the installer is present (search for &amp;ldquo;Calamares&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Installer&amp;rdquo; in the Plasma menu) No Sabayon artwork is present, plasma is vanilla Please, if you encounter other issues let us know, Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Plasma 5.4, available on Plasma5 Sabayon community repository</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that Plasma 5.4 is available on Sabayon Plasma5 community repository.
Plasma 5.4
The KDE team announced on 25 August the release of Plasma 5.4:
This release of Plasma brings many nice touches for our users such as much improved high DPI support, KRunner auto-completion and many new beautiful Breeze icons. It also lays the ground for the future with a tech preview of Wayland session available. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping a few new components such as an Audio Volume Plasma Widget, monitor calibration tool and the User Manager tool comes out beta.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
