<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>equo on Mudler blog</title>
    <link>https://mudler.pm/tags/equo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in equo on Mudler blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 07:09:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mudler.pm/tags/equo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1] Building Gentoo and Sabayon packages in your machine locally or remotely with Docker and Cloud Services</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 07:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</guid>
      <description>With spawning a compilation, the second line (with&amp;hellip; fusion809 - Nov 4, 2015
With spawning a compilation, the second line (with the package you wish to merge) is it possible to point to a specific version of a package. For example, atm I&amp;rsquo;d like to merge app-editors/atom-1.2.0 from the Sabayon overlay, do I have to enter it as `app-editors/atom-1.2.0 &amp;ndash;overlay sabayon` or `=app-editors/atom-1.2.0 &amp;ndash;overlay sabayon`?
In section 3 I think you gave incorrect syntax, although it may be because of formatting limitations imposed by blogger.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Part 1] Building Gentoo and Sabayon packages in your machine locally or remotely with Docker and Cloud Services</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2015 07:09:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/11/part-1-building-gentoo-and-sabayon.html</guid>
      <description>As previously anticipated in the previous blog post, here i explain what&amp;rsquo;s going on with Sabayon Docker images, and how can the Official Sabayon images help you in developing/deploying your application. In this article, i&amp;rsquo;ll show how to build Sabayon/Gentoo packages using Docker.
I&amp;rsquo;ll cover five cases and will be divided in differents articles:
You want to build packages locally You want to remotely build packages You want to host an overlay or a Sabayon repository and want your packages to get built on each push to the git repository You want to track remote repository changes and test (useful if you can&amp;rsquo;t setup a webhook) Setup an Entropy repo with a Docker image, and how to mantain packages In future, i&amp;rsquo;ll write also a post also on how to track the packages remotely with CircleCi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabayon is moving to KDE Plasma 5.4</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 10:36:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/09/sabayon-is-moving-to-kde-plasma-54.html</guid>
      <description>Sabayon is officially moving to Plasma 5, please read if you are a KDE Sabayon user.
KDM is going to be removed! migrate to SDDM now!
Yes, finally we are moving on.
While KDE 4 was a pretty stable DM, Plasma 5 brings awesomeness and, if you didn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, it&amp;rsquo;s the future.
From KDM to SDDM We tried to do our best to make the transition as smooth as possible and automatic, but if your system just got broken here is why: the KDE team announced SDDM as the default KDE display manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KDE Plasma 5.4, available on Plasma5 Sabayon community repository</title>
      <link>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 05:03:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mudler.pm/2015/08/kde-plasma-54-available-on-plasma5.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m glad to announce that Plasma 5.4 is available on Sabayon Plasma5 community repository.
Plasma 5.4
The KDE team announced on 25 August the release of Plasma 5.4:
This release of Plasma brings many nice touches for our users such as much improved high DPI support, KRunner auto-completion and many new beautiful Breeze icons. It also lays the ground for the future with a tech preview of Wayland session available. We&amp;rsquo;re shipping a few new components such as an Audio Volume Plasma Widget, monitor calibration tool and the User Manager tool comes out beta.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
